# **Adam Bradbury**

f.adambrad@gmail.com 385-215-5247 Denver, CO

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

# **Summary**

Full stack developer skilled in writing, clean, testable code. Experienced with React, jQuery, Node, vanilla JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to become part of a team of dedicated developers tackling interesting challenges. While I'm relatively new to tech, less than two years, I am not inexperienced. I have ample experience leading teams, working on teams, along with clients to achieve a variety of different goals and deliverables.

#### **Tech Skills**

**Advanced:** JavaScript, React, Redux, React-Native, jQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs. **Proficient:** MongoDB and PostgreSQL, TDD with Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Jest, TravisCl, Linux/Ubuntu and ES6.

### **Recent Full Stack Projects**

Mood Cloud:

A full stack emotional well-being app for students and teachers. Mood Cloud allows students to track their emotional state overtime. The app also provides channels of communication between students and teachers in times of crisis or despair.

- Front-end stack: React, Redux, Socket.io, and React D3.
  - Used redux for state management. Socket.io for real-time communication messaging and React D3 to visually render student data in a word cloud.
- Back-end stack: Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, JWT Authentication, Socket.io
  - Used MongoDB to store both teacher and student information. Mongoose to refer between schema, JWT for authentication, and created a Socket.io server with events to maintain real-time communication.
- Live demo: Mood Cloud

Sitter Finder:

A full stack app for parents searching for nearby sitters and sitters looking for work. The app provides the means for parents and sitters to create a personal profile and search for opportunities based on location.

- Front-end stack: React, Redux
  - Used Redux for state management combined with Redux Forms for user signup/login
- Back-end stack: Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express
  - Used MongoDB for data storage and flexible api development. Mongoose to reference across schema.
- Live Demo: <u>Sitter Finder</u>

Hola Mundo:

A Spanish language learning app built with a spaced repetition algorithm to enhance learning.

- Front-end stack: React, Redux
  - Used redux for state management and React Router to link components
- Back-end stack: Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express
  - Used MongoDB to store user progress based on a algorithm employing spatial repetition by way of a linked list.
- Live Demo: Hola Mundo

Simply Schedule A simple mobile scheduling app for managers to schedule employees and text them their schedule. Built using Android Studio.

- Front-end stack: React-Native, Redux, Android Studio
  - Used redux for state management. React navigation drawer included to navigate between pages
- Back-end stack: Firebase
  - Used Firebase for authentication and data management.
- Code: GitHub

### **Education**

Remote

September 2017 - February 2018

# Thinkful Engineering Immersion

THINKFUL

• Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, RESTful API, plus algorithms & data structures.

• Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

University of Denver

Denver, CO

Master of Arts in Intercultural and International Communication

November 2014

Relevant Coursework: Intercultural Communication, Program Evaluation, Program Management, Quantitative Research Methods, and Applied Field Methods

2013-2015 IIC Dean's Graduate School Scholarship

**Utah State University** *Bachelor of Science in Psychology* 

Logan, UT May 2005

Minor in Spanish

# **Employment**

CraftWorks Foundation

Broomfield, CO

Senior Manager

April 2015 - September 2017

- Oversaw strategic planning, execution, and evaluation of programs, events, and fund development.
- Guided and managed a team of direct reports tasked with executing programs essential to the success of the Foundation's goals.
- Oversaw and grew the employee hardship program for those in financial crisis due to an unexpected emergency.

Peace Corps

Tetovo, Macedonia

TEFL Volunteer November 2010-November 2012

- Worked collaboratively with teachers to develop more dynamic student-centered lessons.
  Served as a high school English teacher and trainer
- Served as Program Director for Macedonian Model UN designed to create positive political dialogue between ethnic communities in post-conflict communities.
- Served as Incoming Peace Corps Volunteer trainer tasked with helping new volunteers adjust and integrate into their new communities

<u>Interests</u>: All things Mountain West: hiking, backpacking, snowshoeing, camping, running with my dog. Additionally, international and local community development, books, music, travel.